There is no gene for the human spirit.
Gattaca is a thriller, science fiction, mystery film directed by Andrew Niccol.
Vincent is an all-too-human man who dares to defy a
system obsessed with genetic perfection.
He is an "In-Valid" who assumes the identity of a member of the genetic elite to pursue
his goal of traveling into space with the Gattaca Aerospace Corporation.
Vincent Freeman, played by Ethan Hawke.
Irene Cassini, played by Uma Thurman.
Jerome Eugene Morrow, played by Jude Law.
Detective Hugo, played by Alan Arkin.
Adult Anton Freeman, played by Loren Dean.
Director Josef, played by Gore Vidal.
Gattaca is a 1997 American dystopian science fiction film written and
directed by Andrew Niccol in his feature directorial debut.
It stars Ethan Hawke and Uma Thurman with Jude Law, Loren Dean, Ernest
Borgnine, Gore Vidal, and Alan Arkin appearing in supporting roles.
The film presents a future society driven by eugenics where children are conceived through
genetic selection to ensure they possess the best hereditary traits of their parents.
The principal character, Vincent Freeman, played by Hawke, was conceived outside the eugenics program and
struggles to overcome genetic discrimination to realize his dream of going into space.
The film draws on concerns over reproductive technologies that facilitate eugenics, and
the possible consequences of such technological developments for society.
It also explores the idea of destiny and the ways in
which it can and does govern lives.
Characters in Gattaca continually battle both with society and with themselves to find their
place in the world and who they are destined to be according to their genes.
The film's title is based on the letters G, A, T, and C, which stand for
guanine, adenine, thymine, and cytosine, the four nucleobases of DNA.
It was a 1997 nominee for the Academy Award for Best Art Direction
and the Golden Globe Award for Best Original Score.
A follow-up series was in development at Showtime,
but has been cancelled as of 2023.
The film explores themes of genetics, cheating,
paraplegic, suicide attempt, dystopia.
The tone is emotional and mind_bending and thought_provoking.